[theme music playing]
[Camia] You're not Lily.
Lily's my daughter.
I have to save her.
[Ivy] If you want to see Lily again,
we need to get out of here.
[Carlotta] Diego found out
that Ivy is Lily.
-[Jepoy] Nanny, Diego's here.
-[Carlotta] Stop him!
[Julio] Where is Miss Aguas,
and what do you know about her?
Answer me!
Even if I knew where Ivy was,
I wouldn't tell you.
You idiot!
Try me. I'm not the same kid
you used to abuse.
[Ivy] Mom, right now
we only have each other.
Just you and me.
[Emilia] Where are you going?
Are you leaving me? You bastard!
When will you stop cheating on me?!
Go on, do it. I'll burn her to ashes!
[Loring] Fooling the Ardientes
like this is no joke.
I'll sort all this out. I'll look for Ivy.
[Loring] How will you find her?
Who knows where she is?
[Diego] She's been missing
for a few days now,
so please tell me where she is.
[man] She went to the old Torillo house
here in San Ildefonso.
[Ivy] Diego? Diego!
Diego, we're here! Diego!
[Emilia] I'll find out
who your mistress is, Raul.
Then you'll see.
[Ivy] Raul's back again. Don't worry, Mom.
I promise I'll find a way to get
out of here so we can find Lily.
[Raul] But first, I'll sort our stuff out.
-I'm hungry.
-You can talk now?
You don't know how happy you've made me.
I should buy us some food.
Then we'll celebrate, okay?
[Emilia] One great move, Emilia. Good job.
[laughs]
Mom, wait! Mom!
-[Ivy] Mom! Mom!
-[Camia groaning]
-Mom! Wait! Don't move!
-[fire whooshing]
-Uh…
-[Camia coughing]
[Ivy and Camia coughing]
Come here. You can do it. Mom.
[Camia coughing and panting]
Come on, Mom. Don't be afraid. Come here.
I'm right here, Mom. Don't be scared.
[Ivy coughing]
Mom. Hurry! We need to find Lily.
Mom. [coughing]
-Come here, Mom.
-[fire whooshes]
-Mom.
-[Camia panting]
This way, Mom.
[Camia coughing]
Hello, Raul?
Come back here. I have a surprise for you.
What are you talking about, Emilia?
Where will I go back?
Oh, come on, Raul! Where else?
Your mistress' house, of course.
[Camia coughs]
[thumping]
[Camia coughing]
Aren't you going to see how she's doing?
Come on, Raul!
Do I have to spell it out for you?
That would be so boring.
Just come back here
so you can see it for yourself.
It's only polite to say goodbye
before she burns in hell.
[fire raging]
You're a monster, Emilia!
Don't you dare do anything to her!
Or else I will kill you!
[laughs]
[Ivy panting]
[Raul] When will you stop killing people?
When will you stop all this?
When will I stop? When will I stop?!
Do you really want to know when, Raul?!
When you finally stop cheating on me!
[suspenseful music playing]
[Camia coughs]
Mom.
-[Camia coughing]
-I'll go first, Mom. [grunts]
-Mom.
[suspenseful music continues playing]
-[Camia coughing]
-Mom.
[phone ringing]
-Nanny Carlotta?
-[Carlotta] Jepoy.
Do you have any news on Ivy?
My gut's telling me that,
if I find Raul, I'll find Ivy too.
-Yeah.
-Emilia went to go look for him.
So I'm going to follow her.
But, Jepoy, a lot of people
are watching your every move right now.
Especially Emilia.
Didn't you say that
you're her bodyguard now?
-Just be careful, Jepoy.
-Yes, Nanny. I will. Bye.
Madrigal.
Where are you going? Didn't I
tell you to keep an eye on Mom?
She's already sleeping, Mayor.
So, I figured maybe I can spend
some time in town for a while.
[tense music playing]
-[Camia coughs]
-Just a little longer, Mom.
We're almost there.
[Camia coughing]
We're safe now, Mom. Mom…
-[Camia coughing]
-Mom…
-Mom?
-[coughing]
We've escaped the fire, Mom.
Let's stay here, Mom.
Mom? Mom!
Mom! Mom! Mom? Mom?! Mom?
Mom?
[Ivy panting]
[panting]
Jasmin! Jasmin! Jasmin!
[sobbing] Jasmin!
Jasmin!
Jasmin! Where are you, Jasmin?! Jasmin!
[wailing] Jasmin!
[wailing]
Jasmin! I'm here, Jasmin!
[grunting]
[clapping and laughing]
Poor thing. How long
have you been seeing each other?
Two years? Five years? Or more?
I bet it's more because
she must've meant a lot
to you to act like that.
So, Raul, do you love her more
than your first mistress?
Does she make your insides quiver?
Like, hmm… Camia?
You remember her?
The woman you used to lust after?
From that family that just
disappeared back in Ardiente?
Mom!
[somber instrumental playing]
Mom? Come on, Mom.
Mom! Mom! Mom!
Mom!
[panics] Mom! Mom! No!
Mom! Mom!
Mom!
-[Ivy sobbing]
-[Camia coughs]
Mom!
[crying] Mom… Mom.
[screams]
I thought you were
going to leave me again.
[Ivy sobbing uncontrollably]
[dramatic music playing]
Diego?!
Diego! Diego! Diego!
-Diego!
-Ivy?
Diego! Diego, help us, please!
Diego, please!
My mother needs help, please!
Diego, please! Diego!
-Mom!
-Ivy, open the door!
Hang on to me.
Ivy, get in!
You're a monster, Emilia!
You're heartless! She was innocent!
Why don't you just leave me alone?
[giggles]
Is your conscience bothering you?
[Emilia laughing]
It doesn't suit you, Raul.
What you need to do is
stop lying and cheating on me.
So we can spare other women from making
an appointment with death!
[laughs]
Goodbye, Raul.
You're a monster, Emilia!
-[Emilia yelps]
-[Raul grunts]
You're a heartless monster!
-[Emilia yelps]
-I'll kill you, you animal!
[Emilia yelping]
-[Emilia grunting]
-[Raul] What?
[coughs]
You bitch!
[Raul grunting]
Ma'am, are you okay?
Stay out of this, you little brat.
I'm her bodyguard.
I won't let you hurt her.
[suspenseful music playing]
Step back.
This isn't over. Keep that in mind.
[exhales sharply]
This isn't over, Emilia!
[suspenseful music playing]
[exhales]
[car engine roars]
Are you okay, Governor?
-[fire crackling]
-[suspenseful music playing]
Ivy, we're in San Ildefonso proper.
But I can't see a hospital anywhere.
Let's just bring her to your place.
-No. Mom won't be safe there.
-What?
Let's go to San Joaquin. Take us there.
My mom will be safe there.
-San Joaquin?
-Yes.
In Bataan? Ivy,
that's an hour away from here.
I don't care. Bring us to San Joaquin.
I have property there.
Mom will be safe there. Please.
Please.
[Julio] Didn't I tell you not to go out?
I said you couldn't leave this house
without my permission.
But, Papa, Raul has a mistress.
Your marital problems bore
the hell out of me, Emilia.
If you find it boring, Papa,
well, for me, it's not.
This is my family. I have to
do everything to save this.
[Julio] Too late.
There's nothing to save
as far as your marriage is concerned.
Because your marriage
is as rotten as trash.
But you're the one who said
I should solve all my problems.
That's why I'm trying to fix this.
In my world,
I have lots of solutions
and answers to problems.
But as for you, you only know
how to do one thing.
Your only solution is to kill.
But then again, what should
I expect from someone like you?
I have no time for your worthless sermons.
Raul!
Ow! Papa.
Remember this.
If you allow that bastard
to keep treating you that way…
I will make your life a living hell.
You're just like your mother.
A willing victim.
The emotional punching bag
of a useless man.
-But I love Raul, Papa!
-Well, I have news for you!
Love is only for those who deserve it.
Let's go, Mom.
Excuse me, Grandpa.
[exhales]
Good morning, ma'am.
-Mom.
-Go on. Help her. Help her.
-[Ivy] Where are the nurses?
-Nurse! Hurry up!
-Come on.
-[Diego] I'll carry her.
[Ivy] Diego, be careful.
-Where should I lay her?
-Over there, sir.
-Miss Aguas, I'm Dr. Faustino.
-Hello, Doc.
I'm the colleague of Dr. Martinez,
Miss Prianka Aguas' doctor.
Doctor, thank you for coming
on such short notice.
Um, you said you and the patient
were trapped in a fire?
Yes. Because of that, she lost
consciousness and collapsed.
So, I had to revive her.
It's definitely smoke inhalation
that affected her lungs,
that's why she's having trouble breathing.
But, with some rest,
she'll be able to recover soon.
[panting]
[Dr. Faustino] So, when she's much better,
we will treat her catatonic depression.
Please, doctor.
Do everything you can to treat my mother.
Yes. We will do that.
[tense music playing]
Excuse me.
Ivy, are you all right?
Yes. I'm fine.
-Ivy, you're hurt.
-It's just a small wound.
It's fine. Thank you.
Ivy, can we talk?
About you, about Miss Camia,
and about Lily.
[tender music playing]
[nurse] Excuse me, Miss Ivy.
The doctor wants to talk to you.
Excuse me.
What if Ivy was inside that house?
Don't say that. Let's not think that way.
But you just said Raul often
went there, so maybe
that's where Camia was! Both her and Ivy!
[phone ringing]
It's Ivy!
-Hello, dear?
-Ivy?
-Dear?
-Nanny Carlotta.
Oh, Ivy!
We were so worried about you.
Where are you?
I'm here at Puerto Del Sol.
[Carlotta] What are you doing there?
Nanny Carlotta, I found my mom.
Raul locked her up in a house.
We were trapped there…
and I couldn't call you
because my phone died.
There was no power supply there.
When we were about to escape,
the house suddenly caught fire.
But don't worry. We're both safe now.
Mom just needs to recover here
in Puerto Del Sol.
Ivy. Do you need any help there?
I'm okay. My staff can take care of us.
Besides, Diego's here too.
He's the one who helped us.
[Jepoy] Diego? Ivy…
Does Diego know the truth about you?
Ivy?
-Ivy.
-All right.
Dear. Just take care, okay?
You know how much
we care about your safety.
Thank you.
[somber music playing]
Ivy, please. I need to know the truth.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, Diego.
I know I've been craving power,
Aunt Claire, because all my life,
Papa deprived me of that.
But I don't deserve
to be treated like this.
Aren't you used to him yet?
You should know by now
how to bounce back every time
you're treated that way.
If I could kill Raul's mistresses,
it means I can do anything, Aunt Claire.
Even if it means killing my own father.
You've tried that before,
and it didn't work.
I can do it again, Auntie.
Emilia. Emilia.
The reason you can't outwit
your father is because
you're too predictable.
Why don't you agree
with what he wants
instead of going against him?
In order for you to get what you want…
you need to play along
with Julio Ardiente.
[unsettling music playing]
[cries]
[breathes deeply]
[unsettling music playing]
I won't be long.
Raul. Please come back.
[crying] Jasmin! Jasmin!
I'm here! Jasmin!
Forgive me, Camia.
Because of me,
Emilia had you killed twice.
But unlike before,
I couldn't save you this time.
Forgive me.
[tender music playing]
-[Diego] Is this Ivy?
-[teacher] Yes, that's her.
-[Ivy] Diego!
-[Diego] Ivy?
Diego! Help us, please!
My mother needs help, please!
I have so much to ask you.
I need answers to my questions.
Please tell me everything.
I'll understand.
[phone ringing]
Hello, Mr. Mayor?
Grandpa, excuse me.
Ivy, I'm so glad to hear from you.
Don't make it too obvious
you missed me, Mr. Mayor.
[Arnaldo] Well, I won't deny that.
Besides, I was worried about you.
I've been trying to reach you
for the past couple of days,
but you won't pick up.
Oh, thank you, Mr. Mayor.
I appreciate your concern for me,
but now, you don't need
to worry about me because I'm fine,
and we're talking.
I think I would be more at ease
if I saw you.
Mr. Mayor, I decided to leave
because I need some alone time.
But you'd defeat its purpose
if you come to me, right?
Okay, fine. I'll see you soon. Okay?
[Ivy] Of course.
I will see you soon, Mr. Mayor.
-Well, where's Miss Aguas?
-She's soul-searching, Grandpa.
Uh… But she said she'll come back soon.
[scoffs] And you believed her?
Arnaldo. You are the predator.
And Miss Aguas is the prey.
And predators are never soft.
You need Miss Aguas for your candidacy.
You heard me right.
You'll be running for senator in my place.
And you need Ivy.
You need Ivy's money
for our plans to push through.
So, sharpen your fangs, and
go and take down your prey.
Ivy. Answer me right now.
Are you Lily?
Please answer me, Ivy.
Are Ivy Aguas and Lily Cruz
the same person?
[tender music playing]
I believe you already know.
Yes, Diego. I'm your old friend, I'm Lily.
[tender music continues playing]
[soft piano music playing]
[breathes heavily]
Why did you lie to me?
I have my reasons.
A lot of reasons.
And even if I told you,
you wouldn't understand?
Ivy! We're not kids anymore.
I'm not a kid.
I can understand
whatever those reasons are!
-I need an answer!
-And I can't give you one.
No, Diego.
Whatever your questions are,
I can't give you any answers.
I'm thankful for the friendship we had.
And I thank you for accepting Ivy.
But now, we should just be happy
to see each other.
That's that, Diego.
I want to know why my friend lied to me.
Why did you pretend to be someone else?
I need to understand Lily.
[nurse] Miss Aguas. It's Miss Camia.
Why? What happened to her?
[Ivy] Doctor. What happened to my mother?
She had an acute urinary tract infection,
which explains the stomach ache.
But she's also showing signs of
malnutrition and renal failure.
These are all complications
brought about by her condition,
catatonic depression.
Doctor, how bad is it?
If her condition doesn't improve,
there's a possibility of kidney failure.
[somber music playing]
Excuse me.
Governor.
[sighs] Did you find it?
But before you say anything…
I want to thank you
for saving me from Raul.
It's nothing, Governor. Just doing my job.
Did you do what I asked you to do?
There were no charred remains
in the building. Not one.
That's impossible! Keep looking!
Don't stop until you can
show me a dead body.
Understand?
I'm sorry, Governor.
I've checked everywhere.
I couldn't find anything there.
You can go there yourself.
Even if you kill me here now,
I still won't be able
to show you anything.
No, I'll find her. And I won't stop
until I wipe my enemies
off the face of the earth.
Papa said all I do is have people killed.
But you know?
The easiest way to get rid
of your enemies is to kill them.
Because when you have,
that means you've won.
[dramatic music playing]
Ivy, wait. Ivy.
Ivy…
Don't touch me.
Ivy, please talk to me.
What's going on?
Do you know why my mother
is like this now?
She was raped, Diego.
[gasps]
She was shot and buried alive.
So, every time I see her suffering…
I remember the people who made her suffer.
Who did this to her?
Ivy, tell me. Who did this to your mother?
You know what, Diego? You should leave.
No.
I won't leave
until you tell me everything.
Why did you come back?
Why did you lie to me?
Who did this to your mother?
Diego, stop it. Please leave.
Ivy, whatever your plans are,
I'm here for you. I'll help you.
Because you're the only one
who believed in me.
Because you're my friend.
And because I love you.
[soft instrumental playing]
You don't know what you're saying, Diego.
I love you.
["Sa'Yo" by Silent Sanctuary playing]
I love you as Lily. I love you as Ivy.
So, please, give me a chance to show I do.
["Sa'Yo" by Silent Sanctuary playing]
You can't love me, Diego.
-Never.
-Why not? Tell me.
["Sa'Yo" by Silent Sanctuary playing]
[song fades]
[Arnaldo] Sure, Grandpa.
I'll make Ivy's acquaintances talk,
and I won't stop
until I get the answers I want.
And then, bring that woman here
to get things done.
Let's find out if she's still loyal to us.
I will, Grandpa.
Emilia, are you lost?
This isn't your house anymore, remember?
Papa. I know you barred me
from entering this house,
but can I talk to you?
Speak.
First, I'd like to apologize, Papa,
for all the mistakes I made.
I know I've made decisions
without asking your permission.
I did it all because…
I just want you to be proud of me, Papa.
And, if you'll just give me
this one last chance, Papa…
I will correct my mistakes.
I could be the best daughter
that you'll ever have, Papa.
[crying] Just one last chance, Papa.
Please forgive me!
[Emilia sniffles]
I'm begging you, Papa!
[Ivy] Doctor. How's my mother?
Let's wait for the test results
from the hospital.
But I have good news.
Her pain is under control.
Um, Miss Aguas, would you recall
when her condition started?
We were separated for 13 years, Doc.
She was kidnapped, and a lot
of things happened after that.
She was raped… and locked up in a house.
She might have been drugged as well.
That's why she's like this now.
Mm… I must be honest with you, Miss Aguas.
Thirteen years is a very long time.
Curing her condition won't be that easy.
Are you saying my mom
won't be able to remember me?
Your mom has what we call
catatonic depression.
And the effect of this condition
is mild temporary memory loss.
So, it means she can only remember events
before the traumatic experience.
So, that means she won't be
able to adapt to new information, then?
She will have a hard time
accepting and processing
new information and memories.
But I can talk to her.
She can understand me.
She can even comprehend things.
That's good.
If she's getting encouragement
from her loved ones,
she might be able to remember past events
and maybe store new memories.
[Emilia crying]
Emilia…
You're such a bad actress. Stop it.
Do you think you can sway me by kneeling?
Get up. Get up!
It's shameful to see a woman
kneeling like that.
And besides, whoever gave you the idea
that I would let you rule
over my town again?
You can't even manage your own family,
much less a town.
Stop your illusions. Fix your life.
That's precisely what
I'm doing right now, Papa.
[exhales sharply] I'm fixing my life.
But how can I do that if you
lock me up in the guest house?
You insult my intelligence
with your stupidity.
Stop this, Emilia. I don't want
to see your face anymore. Guard!
-[Emilia] Papa, please.
-Hold it.
-Wait. Hold on.
-Grandpa.
-Stop.
-Please. That's enough.
Don't side with your mother
if you don't want her failures
to rub off on you.
With all due respect,
she's the victim here.
I don't think she's the one
who should be punished.
You really want to help your mother?
Don't wipe her tears.
Fix her problems.
[tense music playing]
Guards.
[Emilia weeping]
[Camia groans]
-Mom?
-[Camia gasps]
Mom. Mom, don't be scared.
It's me. It's… It's Ivy.
Ivy?
Yes, Mom. Ivy.
Do you remember me?
But Ivy isn't my real name.
My name was changed to Ivy
when I got adopted.
My real name is Lily.
Mom, it's me. I'm Lily.
Your daughter, Lily. Do you remember me?
No.
You're not my daughter Lily.
But…
But you…
when the house was burning…
you helped me.
You saved my life.
Thank you, Ivy.
There was another man, right?
He helped us too.
It was Diego.
Where is he?
I want to thank him too.
Diego.
Don't leave yet.
My mother wants to see you.
[crying]
Camia, I know… I know you're still alive.
[Ivy] Careful, Mom.
Mom…
he's the man who helped us.
[Raul] I know you're still alive.
[sniffles]
I…
I love you so much.
Thank you for helping us.
That was very kind of you.
You, Ivy, and you…
Diego.
I'll always be here for you and Ivy.
[groans]
-Mom?
-It hurts.
-You're having a headache?
-Yes.
[Ivy] Where does it hurt? Okay. Come here.
-Mrs. Camia.
-[Ivy] Get some rest.
Mrs. Camia, are you okay?
Mrs. Camia?
[breathes heavily]
[tense music playing]
Mrs. Camia?
[tense music continues playing]
You're more beautiful up close.
Sir, please take your hands off me.
I'm just saying you're beautiful.
I said take your hands off me!
Don't touch me! Let me go! Let me go!
[tense music playing]
-[Camia screams]
-Mom! Mom.
-You bastard! Get away from me!
-Mrs. Camia!
Mom, he helped us!
-[Diego] Mrs. Camia.
-[screams] Raul, you bastard!
If it weren't for you,
I wouldn't be like this!
Get away from me! Leave! Leave!
Doc! Mom! Mom! Mom!
-[Dr. Faustino] Take her inside.
-[Camia] Let me go!
-Careful!
-[Camia] Ouch! Ouch!
[Ivy] Mom!
[tense music playing]
Let me go! [screams]
-Be careful.
-Let me go!
-[Ivy] Mom. Mom.
-[Camia screaming]
-Put her down.
-[Camia screams]
-Stop!
-Mom.
[screaming]
[Dr. Faustino] It's okay. Just relax.
[Camia screams]
Doc, what's happening?
What's happening to my mother?
Seeing Diego might've triggered a memory.
These memories are confusing for her,
so the more she tries to understand them,
the more her brain is in
overdrive and gets strained.
That explains her behavior.
So, what do you suggest?
We can't tell her anything about the past?
[Dr. Faustino] Not exactly.
But it shouldn't be abrupt.
The unfolding of memories
should be gradual, or else,
she'll get stressed.
Stress triggers anxiety.
So, tell me. What should we do?
Well, we can do therapy, gradual therapy,
so she can regain her buried memories.
Okay, Doc. We will do whatever it takes.
We'll do everything for my mom to recover.
Yes, we'll do that.
[Raul crying]
[sniffles]
Is that because you feel guilty
for hurting Mom?
Or sad that your mistress is dead?
[tense music playing]
In case you don't know…
you're a good-for-nothing husband.
[tense music playing]
and in my opinion…
you're a worthless father too.
Do you understand? Don't ever forget that.
Mom keeps killing people because of you.
What do you do in return?
You know, Arnaldo, I'm your father.
You shouldn't talk to me that way.
-You don't understand that--
-Really?
Father?
No.
Just so we're clear…
Just so we're clear,
I gave up on you a long time ago.
[tense music playing]
[exhales]
-Please take care of her.
-Okay.
Ivy. Is it true, Ivy?
Is it true my dad's the reason
your mother's this way now?
Answer me, Ivy.
Is it true?
Lily, please answer my question.
Tell me the truth.
Ivy. Please tell me.
You want the truth?!
You want answers?!
Didn't you hear her?
Yes! My mother is like that
because of Raul!
Because of your good-for-nothing father!
[dramatic music playing]
[Emilia] I need to find out who
filed the police report against Raul.
Do you know what Jasmin's full name is?
Camia Cruz, a woman
Mom killed a long time ago.
She's still alive.
[Emilia] Because I'm the one
who had her killed,
I need to bury her back
in the grave she crawled out of!
[Diego] If it weren't for your womanizing,
none of this would've happened
to Lily or our family!
[Raul] Wait, what family?
You aren't related to the Ardientes.
[Jepoy] We need to keep a
closer eye on your mom.
Emilia knows she was
in that burning house.
-And she suspects that she's still alive.
-Does she?
Then I need to be ready in case
Emilia figures us out.
[theme music playing]